SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Career Overview

Over seven years of experience in pre-sales as a solutions architect having supported all aspects of sales activities and sales channels development for the company products and services. Possesses the ability to build and maintain business relationships with decision makers and influencers. Objective - Seeking a position that will benefit from my strong technical and pre sales engineering experience to create sales business strategies and develop customer base, marketing tools and product launching.

Technical Skills

Skills

Experience Total Years Last Used

HTTP/Apache, DNS/BIND, SSH, SNMP, DNS, DHCP, FTP

Skills

Active Directory, Architect, automation, avenue, Business writing, CNE, change management, Novell CNE, Strong communication skills, CA, Hardware, content, client, clients, Data Processing, databases, Delivery, designing, documentation, DNS, driving, Eclipse, Engineer, XML, features, government, Information technology, Instructor, IQ, JAVA, JSP, Javascript, LDAP, managing, Management Training, Access, Microsoft Exchange, Microsoft Office, Microsoft SQL, Microsoft Windows, MySQL, NetBios, Enterprise, network servers, Networking, Novell, Novell Netware, OS, Oracle, excellent Presentation skills, printers, Project Lead, project management, proposals, quick, Red Hat Linux, requirements gathering, RFP, Sales Engineer, Self-starter, servers, SOAP, Software engineering, Sun Solaris, SQL, SSL, Sun, Sun Microsystems, TCPIP, user training, technical documentation, Tomcat, troubleshooting, validation, VM, WebLogic, written, writer

Work Experience

Senior Software Engineer Jan 2010 to Feb 2015

Johnson & Johnson i1/4 Cambridge, MA

- Performed the roles of Identity Delivery Engineer, Identity Manager SME, Project Manager, Identity Management Training Instructor and second tier support engineer.
- Enhancements that I was responsible for implementing included the streamlining of onboarding new user accounts, adding automation that closed audit compliancy gaps and reduced the complexity involved in access changes throughout a user's account lifecycle.
- Applications involved included vendor applications as well as in house applications installed locally as well as cloud based and SaaS
 applications such as Clarity and Microsoft Office 365.
- These enhancements directly correlated to user productivity and IT resources needed to manage user accounts in the enterprise.
- Utilizing my experience as an Identity Manager Training Instructor as well as documentation writer, I created and delivered targeted end user training sessions for the end user community at Discover on key enhancements to the Identity Management releases being rolled out.
- This included creating end user quick guide documents, end user self-paced training modules and the technical documentation of support procedures.
- Through this use of information published and presented to the end user community it increased productivity by giving the user community
 clear understanding in training as well as centralized reference material of how to use the features used to manage user access in the
 enterprise.
- Utilizing my experience in project management, my involvement encompassed the change and release management in the delivery of new features.
- My role here included the capturing and documenting requirements in a trace requirements matrix, designing a solid user acceptance plan, facilitated the user acceptance testing process, coordinating resources utilization, delivery of the release changes which included detailed change management implementation plans, implementation validation, release management of the changes and support turnover documentation.
- My responsibilities included working with various business units in requirements gathering, vender resource collaboration, testing and implementation needed for enabling single sign on for the applications in that business unit utilizing CA Single Sign On.
- Single Sign On for common applications in enterprise increased user productivity and reduced IT resources involved in account / password management.
- The applications included vendor applications as well as in house applications installed locally as well as cloud based and SaaS applications such as Clarity and Microsoft Office 365.
- This role encompassed the support and troubleshooting of user access across the identity and access management software as well as LDAP directories, virtual directories and Active Directory.
- Additionally I was a key resource utilizing the Sailpoint Identity IQ governance software along with other team members for the
 configuration of applications to deliver automated certifications for critical applications in the enterprise thus automating many compliancy
 regulations and audit control requirements for those applications.

Pre-Sales Engineer / Principle Identity Delivery Specialist Jan 2009 to Jan 2010 Bickford Senior Living $i^1\!/4$ Lansing Charter , MI

- Was instrumental in securing new opportunities in the role of a Pre-Sales Engineer demonstrating the key features of given solution aligned to
 customer needs then performing custom demonstrations of a given product set as applicable to the customer needs and finally responding to
 requests for proposals (RFPs), requests for information (RFIs) as requested by the potential customer/client.
- Then once a customer engagement was secured, instrumental in creating a statement of work (SOW) for a multi-phased implementation of the solution for the customer.
- Additionally, performed the roles of Identity Architect, Identity Project Lead, Lead Implementation Expert, Project Manager and Identity Management Training Instructor.
- In 2009 the Identity practice at SimpleSoft Solutions, Inc.
- was sold to Collier Computing Company.

- In the Identity Management space I was the lead pre-sales engineer for Collier, driving initial product placement discussions, requirements gathering breakout sessions, coordinated stakeholder to gather and document requirements, creating product demonstrations, coordination of POC's, and responsible for the content of RFP and SOW related documents for the potential engagements.
- In this role I was able to secure new Identity business for the company that spanned corporate, government and education sector clients.
- Once an engagement in the Identity Management space started, my role often changed to that of the Identity Architect, lead implementer and often project manager.
- I facilitated and coordinated the successful completion of several phases of a multi-phased Identity Management implementation for corporate, education and government sector engagements.
- In each of these implementations the lifecycle management of user identities was centralized through the automation of user accounts and access in the enterprise.
- These implementations included: onboarding / claiming of new accounts, changes in account access throughout the account lifecycle, concluding with the off boarding / sun setting the account and access in the enterprise.
- The automation of the current process, which had previously been extremely manual in nature, greatly reduced the IT cost of managing user accounts.
- As the SME in the identity space for Collier, I was the lead training technical instructor, delivering many of the official Sun Microsystems Identity Management implementation and delivery classes.
- This provided additional training revenue for the company as well as in many cases provided a solid avenue in which to pursue additional Identity management business.

Jan 2000 to Jan 2009 Simplesoft Solutions, Inc i¹/₄ City , STATE IT Career Jan 1995 to Jan 2000

 My IT career before entering the identity / access / governance space included supporting, migrating and implementing Novell and Microsoft network servers, connected printers and computers which early in my career encompassed ten highly visible business units with around 500 end users for a major health care company.

Education and Training

Diploma, Computer Data Processing 1994 City, State Computer Data Processing Successful completion of the Computer Data Processing program at MBTI in Milwaukee, WI. Graduated from that institution with honors.